

Alex Elkin (He/Him)

Front-End Developer · Valencia, ES

- alex@elkin.dev
- elkin.dev
- in AlexElkin

- +34 698 999 059
- @zakamsky

About Me

Responsible frontend developer with mentoring experience. My focus is on creating engaging, accessible & performant interfaces for humans.

My experience includes the development of adaptive cross-browser applications, with a focus on reliability and performance. I try to see each project as a set of independent reusable components, such an implementation increases stability and facilitates refactoring.

Currently working on egambling with Angular and TypeScript. I do a lot of research to keep my skills up to date and expand my horizons.

I like projects with good structure and room for creativity.

Skills

- HTML (njk/twig)
- CSS (scss/sass)
- JavaScript
- Angular
- React
- typeScript
- UI/UX

- JAMstack
- A11y Accessibility
- npm
- Gulp/Webpack
- Git
- Email's markup
- Teamwork

- Flexibility
- Professionalism
- Responsibility
- Critical thinking
- Problem solving
- Mentoring
- Learn on the fly

Work Experience

02/2022 - PRESENT

Frontend developer

Brain Rocket · Limassol, Cyprus

(remote from Valencia)

- Develop independent Angular components for B2B projects, teamwork in two-week sprints, code reviews, refactoring Email's markup.
- Optimized the performance of transitions, built a modular email layout system with njk template engine. Revealed the problem of gap in flexbox and performance of css filters.

07/2020 - 01/2022

Fullstack web developer

Ihor · Moscow, Rus

- o Development and support of websites for the services of the customer. Revision and update legacy projects, set up on cms WordPress, JAMstack (11ty) and integration with various services. Optimized page load speed according to GooglePageSpeed.
- Implemented kanban task management for the development team. Developed universal independent blocks components for typical tasks.

01/2020 - PRESENT

Mentor

HTML academy · Saint Petershurg RII

y *y*, ...

(remote)

Mentor in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and email's markup intensives.
 Helping and motivating students, answering their questions, code-reviewing and pull requests approving.

Regularly ranked among the top mentors based on student feedback and 10/10 grades received.
 Received a commendation for contribution to course development.

05/2019 - 06/2020

Front-End Developer

PrestaWeb · Ekaterinburg, RU

- Frontend development, markup approval from markup developers, integration with backend api and CMS PrestaShop. Legacy projects support, working with time logging, teleconferencing, teamwork.
- I have developed modern layouts using the fallback to support older browsers.
 Tweaked the usability of the corporate wiki, improved readability through typography.

Education

04/2021 - 10/2021

JS, JsProMarathon, React, ReactProMarathon

Marathons by Zar Zakharov · online

09/1997 - 06/1999

Information systems and programming

Permskiy khimiko-tekhnologicheskiy tekhnikum · Perm, RU

Interests

Languages

- Archery
- Runing
- Podcasts about web development
- Hiking and cycling
- Table top games

- Spanish
- EnglishRussian

© Alex Elkin

elkin.dev